# **Ashutosh Kumar**

## DevOps Engineer

I am an experienced IT professional with over 7 years of experience in the software industry, including 3 years of specialized expertise in DevOps. Currently working as a Technical Consultant at Precisely, I am actively seeking a role as a DevOps Engineer where I can apply my extensive skills and drive innovation within the field.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Precisely Software & Data India P. Limited - Technical Consultant Project - EnterWorks July 2022 - PRESENT

• As a Technical Consultant, I manage global EnterWorks installations, ensuring seamless, successful deployments. My responsibilities include careful planning, technical expertise, and proactive communication.

Technologies worked on - SQL Server, Installer, Windows OS

Precisely Software & Data India P. Limited - Software Engineer Project - Web Mapping Application

May 2020 – June 2022

- I created InstallShield installers for a web mapping app, ensuring seamless installations. Managed CI/CD pipelines with TeamCity, reducing manual work by 70% and boosting efficiency.
- Managed Git Continuous Integration (CI) and configured custom runners using Docker.
- Set up a TeamCity project for Checkmarx scans.

**Technologies worked on**: TeamCity, GIT, PowerShell, Checkmarx, InstallShield, Docker, Windows & Linux OS

## Pitney Bowes Software India P. Limited - SDE Intern

Project - Cross Border E-commerce

February 2016 - April 2020

- Automated the software build process using Jenkins, including configuring and managing build jobs, setting up build triggers, integrating with version control systems, and executing build scripts.
- Created and managed branches for software development in version control systems to organize and isolate different features, bug fixes, or releases.

Technologies worked on: Jenkins, SVN

#### **EDUCATION**

Uttar Pradesh Technical University, Lucknow
B. Tech in Computer Science and Engineering, Graduated in 2015

#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

\*\*AWS Resource Usage Tracker using shell script\*\*

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/AshutoshKumar99/AWSResourceUsage">https://github.com/AshutoshKumar99/AWSResourceUsage</a>
\*\*Running NodeJS Tests/CI with GitHub Actions/Workflow\*\*

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/AshutoshKumar99/github-actions-nodejs-tests">https://github.com/AshutoshKumar99/github-actions-nodejs-tests</a>

ADDRESS: Noida, Sector 66,

Uttar Pradesh Mobile: 9936514482

ashutoshkumar101094@gmail.co

m

www.linkedin.com/in/ashutosh-

kumar-b0084212b

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Cloud Computing: **AWS**CICD: **Jenkins, TeamCity**Containerization: **Docker**Scripting Languages: **Bash** 

VCS: **GIT, SVN**IaC Tool: **Terraform**Configuration Management:

Ansible

Application Server: **Apache** 

**Tomcat** 

Familiar with **GitHub Actions**Operating Systems: **Windows**, **Linux** 

### AWARDS

**R&R** Award for outstanding contributions to Cross Border E-commerce at Pitney Bowes.

**Thumbs Up Award** for outstanding performance on the Web Mapping Application project.

**Spot Award** from Precisely for exceptional performance on the EnterWorks project at Precisely

#### **CERTIFICATES**

HashiCorp Certified: **Terraform Associate** 

**AWS Certified Cloud** 

**Practitioner** 

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Hindi